# **Daniel Rossano**

Edmonds, WA - 860.558.0400 - daniel.rossano10@gmail.com - https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-rossano-6a192228/

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am a passionate developer & engineer seeking to leverage my strong analytical experience, leadership skills and efficiency improvement ideas to increase company profitability. I have 11+ years of broad front-end and back-end experience including Python programming, ReactJS, data analytics, data engineering, process improvements, machine learning/AI and predictive forecasting.

#### **SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES**

Python, AWS, SQL, Azure, Snowflake, MongoDB, Data Mining, Web Scraping, React JS, Next JS, Terraform, Webex, Tailwind CSS, Cosmos, Apache Airflow, Databricks, Pyspark, R, Hive, Presto, Kafka, Postgres SQL, Photoshop/website front-end design, SAP, Tableau, Veeva, Oracle, Jupyter Notebook, Big Data analysis, Data Warehousing, Data Modelling, Process improvements, Machine learning, Flask, Django, Fast API, Artificial Intelligence, A/B testing, Advanced MS Office Suite (Sharepoint, Excel, Access, Powerpoint and Power BI), Lean/six-sigma, Networker and team leader.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES**

**Senior Data Engineer –** March 2023 – Present

**Symetra** – Bellevue, WA

- Designed and developed an AWS hosted React JS front-end and Fast API back-end internal app to production used by over 1000 employees. My Stack includes React, Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Snowflake, and Fast API.
- Redesigned our app's AWS architecture by removing 4 lambda and 4 API gateways and replaced with a single Fargate instance running a multi service app in ECS, all built using CDK.

**Data Engineer – September 2022 – March 2023** 

United Health Care - Redmond, WA

- Involved in designing and deploying a multitude of applications utilizing almost all of the AWS stack including EC2, Route53, S3, RDS, Dynamo DB, Athena, Lambda, Glue, focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance and auto scaling in AWS cloud formation/Terraform.
- Build AWS automated data pipelines utilizing AWS S3, Lambda, Glue and Athena to transfer on prem data into the cloud for more efficient data processing.
- Developed a single page application with Fast API for displaying JSON retired data using React JS.
- Automate provisioning and repetitive tasks using Terraform and Python.
- Using software engineering best practices using Bitbucket and Github.
- Provisioning Spark clusters to build the On-Demand Data warehouse and provide the data for our Data Science team.

# **Senior Commercial Data Analyst –** November 2020 – September 2022

Seagen – Bothell, WA

- Built and deployed a python script that will replace the use for our department's Dell Boomi system. The script is currently on track for saving Seagen over 1,000+ hours in labor for the year of 2022.
- Built out the data and reporting infrastructure from the ground up using Power BI and SQL to provide real-time insights into the product, marketing channels and business KPIs.
- Built Power Automate workflows to solve daily repeatable tasks, saving the company and my team hours of time.
- Performed statistical analysis on sales territory performance using supervised learning methods such as regression, classification, and decision trees using Python's Scikit-learn.
- Created a Python script that automatically compares two separate data sources and automatically notifies users if any errors are found via email.
- Built an automated email notification program that notifies sales team members of product status in their territory using Python and SQL. This process replaces the sales team from checking a power BI report manually.
- Worked with Petabyte sized data using Spark and Apache Hadoop to identify gaps and inconsistencies, provided data insights, and provided product solutions.
- Built and implemented Apache Airflow DAGs to streamline Commercial workflows. Helped eliminate unnecessary processes and helped reconfigure our groups ETL pipeline layout saving over 30 minutes a week.

- Analyzed sales members' data using Power BI/SQL and Snowflake while navigating multiple data sources.
- Created and implemented test plans to support Seagen's Commercial sales team's Power BI database.

# Method Process Analyst/Project Engineer - March 2019 - November 2020

#### The Boeing Company – Everett, WA

- Performed sophisticated ad-hoc or ongoing custom analyses against factory efficiency to support business stakeholders and created visual displays to present data using Tableau.
- Designed and populated specific tables, databases for collection, tracking and reporting of data.
- Managed the planning and development of design and procedures for metrics reports.
- Investigated and conducted studies on the forecasts, demand, and capital of products.
- Applied Lean processes to achieve improvements to drive quality and managing the cost, decreasing it 10% in one year.
- Networked with multiple departments to build relationships among the peers.
- Worked with cross-functional groups to expedite parts to the factory that resulted in improvement of our timeframe and saved \$100,000 in expenses.

# **Project Manager - October 2017 – May 2018**

# Information Science & Service (ISS) - New Hudson, MI

- Led a Standard Work Instructions Project.
- Developed a SharePoint site to house the Standard Work Instructions, making them accessible globally, and adding version control.
- Developed metrics to track SharePoint utilization.
- Identified existing workflows and wrote Standard Work Instructions for the newly optimized workflows and presented data using Power BI.
- Proposed solutions to improve system efficiencies and reduce total expenses.

# Data Analyst - September 2014 - September 2016

# QuEST Global Engineering – Windsor Locks UTAS, CT

- Managed a team of four and oversaw component removal data collection and performed analysis.
- Presented data and conclusions to team to improve strategies and operations.
- Optimized data collection procedures and generated reports on a weekly, monthly, and quarterly basis.
- Identified existing workflows, mapped, and tracked.

# Senior Engineer - October 2013 - September 2014

- Improved data mining processes, resulting in a 15% decrease in time needed to infer insights from customer data used to develop design change strategies.
- Saved QuEST over \$90,000 in process improvements in 2014.
- Optimized workflows to enhance productivity/efficiency/speed.
- Developed metrics to track project speed through engineering start-of-work to handoff.
- Streamlined and managed supplier's inventory and processes and implemented cost savings improvements resulting in \$10,000 dollars saved. .

#### **Project Engineer** - March 2012 – October 2013

- Constructed technical documents for mechanical and electrical systems on the 787-8 Boeing Dreamliner.
- Facilitated team meetings, worked with engineers to establish a plan of schedule, helped engineers write technical documents, tracked group progress until project completion.
- Managed a hardware-tracking Excel database, cross-referenced multiple software programs, and collaborated with engineers to ensure schedule and deadlines were met.

#### **RECOGNITION & AWARDS**

- Awarded Team impact award for my Python automation improvements 2022
- Received over \$1,000 dollars in awards for creation of process improvement tools, 2014-15
- Recognized for expanding an underutilized contract and became the customer's focal contact. As a result, a new QuEST employee was hired to help serve the customer's expanded needs, 2013

QuEST, Employee of the Month, December 2012

#### **EDUCATION**

**Python programming certification –** University of California, Irvine – March 2022 - **PCEP -** Python for Data Science, Web and Core Programming

- Schema design and high-dimensional data modeling using machine learning techniques.
- Projects included multiclass classification using machine learning methods, data wrangling and compiling hundreds of CSV files using Python, and logistic regression model creation and interpretation.

University of Connecticut – Storrs, CT – December 2010 - BA, Sociology focused in Social Statistics

Manchester Community College – Manchester, CT – May 2009 AA in Liberal Arts & Science focus in Business Studies